Prepare to be blown out of the water.
Pirates of the Caribbean: The Curse of the Black Pearl is a
adventure, fantasy, action film directed by Gore Verbinski.
When wily Captain Barbossa steals Jack Sparrow's ship and kidnaps the governor's beautiful daughter, Elizabeth, her
childhood friend Will Turner joins forces with Jack to save her and recapture Jack's ship, the Black Pearl.
Jack Sparrow, played by Johnny Depp.
Barbossa, played by Geoffrey Rush.
Will Turner, played by Orlando Bloom.
Elizabeth Swann, played by Keira Knightley.
Norrington, played by Jack Davenport.
Governor Weatherby Swann, played by Jonathan Pryce.
Pirates of the Caribbean: The Curse of the Black Pearl is a 2003
American fantasy swashbuckler film directed by Gore Verbinski.
Produced by Jerry Bruckheimer and distributed by Buena Vista Pictures via the Walt Disney Pictures label, the film is based on the
Pirates of the Caribbean attraction at Disney theme parks and is the first film in the Pirates of the Caribbean series.
Starring Johnny Depp, Geoffrey Rush, Orlando Bloom, and Keira Knightley, it follows pirate Jack Sparrow (Depp) and the
blacksmith Will Turner (Bloom), as they attempt to rescue the kidnapped Elizabeth Swann (Knightley).
The trio encounters Captain Hector Barbossa (Rush) and the Black
Pearl crew who are afflicted by a supernatural curse.
Executives at Walt Disney Studios drafted a rough
treatment for  the film in 2000.
A script was developed by Jay Wolpert in 2001, and was
rewritten by Stuart Beattie in early 2002.
Around that time, the producer Jerry Bruckheimer became involved in the project.
He brought in screenwriters Ted Elliott and Terry Rossio, who
had drafted a premise for the film in the 1990s.
Elliott and Rossio added the curse to the script to align
the film's story with the theme park ride.
Verbinski eventually signed on as the director.
Filming took place from October 2002 to March 2003 in Saint Vincent and
the Grenadines and on sets in Los Angeles, California.
Pirates of the Caribbean had its world premiere at the Disneyland
Resort in Anaheim, California, on June 28, 2003.
It was theatrically released in the United States on July 9.
Despite low expectations, the film was a massive box-office success: it grossed $654.3
million worldwide, making it the fourth-highest-grossing film of 2003.
It received generally positive reviews from critics, and
Depp won a Screen Actors Guild Award.
He was also nominated for his performance at the
Academy Awards, BAFTAs, and Golden Globes.
Pirates of the Caribbean was also nominated for
additional Academy Awards and BAFTAs.
The film was followed by four sequels: Dead Man's Chest (2006), At World's End
(2007), On Stranger Tides (2011), and Dead Men Tell No Tales (2017).
The film explores themes of blacksmith, gold, exotic island, governor, skeleton.